"Previously on The Mentalist..."
- I'm Patrick.
- Hey, Patrick. Lorelei.
Perhaps we can see
each other again.
I do what Red John
tells me to do.
- Accept his friendship.
- It's that easy?
Sure. And you'll need
to bring him a gift.
- What kinda gift?
- Teresa Lisbon's dead body
would be the perfect thing.
Good luck, Teresa. Love you.
Well, the question remains,
why did Jane do this?
- Orders from Red John?
- I don't know what to think.
I want arrest warrants prepped
for every single member
of that CBI team, dead or alive.
FBI! Nobody move!
CBI! Don't shoot!
We're CBI agents!
- You're making a terrible mistake.
- Get out.
- Got the gift?
- Red John in there?
Our fake deaths were a ruse
to trap Red John, and it worked.
"What if you and I were friends?
Imagine the life we could lead."
Go to hell.
You're gonna break down
and you're gonna tell us
everything you know
about Red John.
You're gonna sing like a bird.
No, lover. I won't.
Yes, you will.
- We're up.
- What?
We have a case.
Now?
You can't talk to her yet anyhow.
The FBI won't let you.
I'll be right there.
You can't leave
your car there.
Hey!
Hey, boys.
- You the responding officer?
- Uh, yes, ma'am.
- Officer Yannick.
- What have we got?
A 911 call came in from this location.
7:33 p.m.
But, uh, nobody spoke.
Door was unlocked, and, uh,
this is how we found 'em.
This is Rex Lango
and, uh, Callie Karlsen.
They both worked together
at the hotel convention center.
Uh, this is her place.
- So the door was already open?
- Yes, sir.
I figure the marks and bruising
on the neck indicate strangulation
and, uh, he got clubbed to death
with the bottle, ah?
Yes. Nice analysis there, Yannick.
Couldn't have killed each other,
could they?
Unlikely. She'd have to be
conscious and active
to hit him with that bottle.
Check out the lipstick
on his cheek.
So it's your classic love triangle.
Third wheel comes in,
finds these two kissing
whacks the rival with the bubbly
chokes out jezebel here.
Yeah, that's pretty much what I...
uh, figured. Yeah.
Jane? Thoughts?
Well, the champagne's
an excellent vintage.
Callie didn't have
a steady boyfriend.
Uh, no spare toothbrush.
She believes poor soul
in a benevolent universe
and she, uh, comes from money.
- Money? She works in a hotel.
- I've seen enough.
We're outta here.
Let forensics do their job.
So, uh, if you need me,
you know where to find me.
- Thank you, officer Yannick.
- You're welcome. My pleasure.
What are you guys doing here?
What are you doing here?
Hey, Teresa.
What's up? You're all under
suspension, aren't you?
We were told to cover your calls.
Suspension? What?
Who are you guys?
FBI. Walk away.
You didn't hear?
The suspensions have been lifted.
The brass made a deal.
Yeah, we heard
that they were talking.
They put a lid
on the whole thing.
It's business as usual.
Suspension's lifted.
So you guys don't need
to be here.
Look, I'm sorry for the mix-up.
Wait. Wait.
You mean to tell me
that after the monumental
crap storm you guys created
they're just gonna let you walk away?
- I'm stunned, frankly.
- I understand.
I mean, you destroyed the career
of a fine FBI agent.
You... you caused the death
of your own boss.
And this one?
This one's got assault, narcotics
- and fraud charges against him.
- All dismissed.
Part of the deal. Phew.
How'd you get
such a sweet deal?
Uh, we got a deal because, uh,
it was the FBI that messed up
not me or the CBI.
The FBI.
- That's right.
- That's incorrect.
- Oh, touché.
- We were this close
to catching Red John
before you blew it.
And even in spite of your interference
we caught Lorelei Martins
- and she's our...
- She's our suspect
- and we want her back.
- You're not getting her.
Oh, we'll see about that.
We'll see.
"We'll see"?
Your inarticulate rage is understandable
but it's misplaced.
You should probably just calm down.
You calm yourself down.
I'm not angry.
No? Your temples are pulsing
like some weird
undersea creature.
If that's not anger,
you should see a doctor.
- Jane, stop.
- Okay, I'm going.
Nice to see you.
Watch this one.
He's a hothead.
I am sorry.
He does that.
- I'm not angry.
- I believe you.
I just think you people
should be in jail
- and not out working cases.
- That's right.
But we're not in jail.
We're here, so keep moving.
Or else what,
you're gonna make us move?
If you like.
Then go ahead.
Make me move.
All right, that's enough.
You're both being childish.
- You take your hands off!
- Get off her!
- Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
- Come on.
- Hey!
- Come on!
Break it up!
- Come on.
- Let it go.
- I'm sorry.
- That's it!
I'll see you back at the office.
Knock it off!
Come on, guys!
- Welcome back.
- Thank you so much.
I could not be less happy
to be back.
Uh...
I'd like to take this opportunity
to thank you for, uh...
- fixing things.
- Yes, sir. We...
You know, I thought
I had, as you say
fixed things
and now I discover that you
and your FBI counterparts
have been fighting?
- At a crime scene?
- Sir, it was...
If I can persuade the FBI
to forget this latest incident
you, Jane, are down
to your very last chance.
And you are only granted
this chance
because to get rid of you now
would be evidence
of the scandal we are trying
so hard to conceal!
Looking on the bright side
we have Lorelei Martins.
She can lead us to Red John.
She knows who he is.
California's most notorious
serial killer caught on your watch.
Well, that remains
to be seen.
But until I negotiate
an arrangement with the feds
you cannot talk to her.
That's the deal!
I understand. But here's the thing.
The FBI can't have her.
In a half an hour, I have to stand up
at a press conference
and lie to the people of California
in order to protect you.
And you are arguing
with me now?
They can't have her.
I will do my best
to keep her, but you have...
I promise, uh, there'll be
no more trouble from me.
I-I won't say a word
at this press conference.
You're damn right you won't
say a word
'cause you won't be there!
"Agent Schultz!"
Alexa.
Hi.
We still have a deal, right?
I'd rather eat spiders,
but, yeah, we still have a deal.
Good, good.
God, you look fabulous,
by the way.
Camera ready.
Is... is my tie straight?
You understand, Gale,
this matter doesn't end here.
You have to give us
Lorelei Martins
or there'll be consequences
down the line.
Consequences for whom?
It was your agents that killed
the best chance we've had yet
of catching Red John.
It was your Agent Darcy
that killed Wainright.
Tragic outcome
in a deadly force situation.
Agent Darcy is devastated.
She's had a nervous collapse,
in fact.
Your people committed
deliberate crimes.
Well, that's debatable.
Look!
We have agreed to a cover-up.
That's the deal.
If you're saying now that...
you're gonna dig this all up again
unless I do your bidding
then no deal.
No, let... let's tell
the truth right now.
An FBI agent shot and killed
a CBI agent
in the midst of a botched operation.
It'll be a huge scandal,
we'll probably lose our jobs
but I'm sure we'll both feel
better for it.
Son of a bitch.
I am very proud to tell you
that last week
in a joint FBI-CBI sting operation
of great complexity and danger
Lorelei Martins,
a close associate
of notorious serial killer
Red John, was arrested.
Tragically, in the course
of that operation
CBI Special Agent in charge
Luther Wainright was shot and killed.
Gale?
Luther Wainright was a good friend
a valued colleague, and we all mourn
his passing deeply.
He's a hero.
As part of the sting operation
one of our operatives, Patrick Jane
had criminal charges
fabricated against him
in order to go undercover
and we apologize to the public
for that deception.
Today, the story
is of the great job done
by these two teams
of consummate professionals
working together in harmony.
Questions?
This working in harmony business
is very hard to believe.
There's a very long public
history of disharmony
between your two bureaus.
That's why they call it history, Josh.
- It's in the past.
- Exactly.
What we're celebrating today
is the dawn of a new era.
Just this morning,
these two teams
began work on another
case together.
A double murder
in Dupont Gardens.
Best of luck on that one, guys.
Go get 'em.
Let's call it a truce, shall we, guys?
I mean, we're all grownups here.
- Yep, sure.
- Yeah.
- Nice place.
- It is.
This is like a bad date. I wish
these bozos would just vanish.
Wow. Four cops.
Must be a red ball, huh?
A red ball?
Well, that's what you guys call
an urgent case, right?
All murder cases are urgent.
Yes, of course. I...
I would never imply otherwise. I...
What can you tell us
about Callie and Rex?
Um, Callie has been with us
two years as a housekeeper.
Reliable. Always upbeat.
Really, uh, just a lovely girl.
Well, a woman, that is.
Uh, Rex Lango
I don't know so well.
He's only been here
a couple weeks
and, uh, works over
in tech support.
But he seems like, you know,
a good fellow.
He... uh, punctual.
Were they friends? Lovers?
Uh, well, I wouldn't know.
Um, you know, you should check
with their workmates.
You and Callie were close?
Yes, me and Callie
were friends.
She was such a good,
kind person.
Poor thing.
Oh, my God.
Did she have any boyfriend troubles
that you know of?
Nuh-unh. Men were always
asking her out
but she would always
say no.
Was anybody bothering her?
Not that she told me.
What was her relationship
with Rex Lango?
- None, I don't think.
- Hmm.
What about Mr. Norris?
Did he have a thing for Callie?
Oh, you think Mr. Norris?
He would ogle her.
But he did that to all the women...
ogle them and, you know,
cop a feel sometimes.
He always asks people out,
but nobody says yes
because he had a girlfriend
once who worked here
and they broke up,
and he fired her butt so fast.
- Hmm.
- You think he did this?
- Did you get anything useful?
- Nope. You?
Nope.
Be right back.
Nah, nothing useful.
Uh, excuse me.
Mr. Norris?
Uh, thank you so much
for your help in the investigation.
I just have a couple more questions
before we go.
- Yeah.
- Um... how many employees
are you responsible for
here at the hotel?
I supervise 210 employees.
Wow. That is a lot.
Yeah. Have you ever seen
your mother naked?
What? No!
Well, we'll leave that alone
for a moment.
Let me ask you this.
Have you ever looked
at Callie Karlsen in a sexual way?
No!
I mean, you know,
she's an attractive...
- woman.
- Sure.
I didn't look away.
So, yes, you looked
at her sexually.
- Uh, have you touched her?
- No!
Why are you shielding your right side?
Are you hiding something?
Hiding?
I'm not hiding anything!
Something. Your... your inside
jacket pocket
- is making you nervous.
- No!
- What do you have in there?
- Uh, w... nothing. Oh. Okay.
A wallet.
Wh-why are you wanting
to hide your wallet from us?
I don't. It's just a wallet.
- Hey, you can't do that.
- It's a gray area.
Okay... there's nothing
in there.
Well, looky here. Callie Karlsen.
That's our girl, isn't it?
Couldn't resist a souvenir, huh?
Okay. I have never seen
that before in my life.
Really? Has this wallet been
out of your possession recently?
No, but... I swear,
I-I've never seen that before.
- I swear to God.
- Well, I tell you what, Mr. Norris.
Why don't we talk some
more downtown
see if we can solve
this mystery?
No. No, no, no. No, no.
I've got a hotel to run.
- I cannot...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait a second.
He's our suspect.
- Looks like he's ours to me.
- No, no. That's not fair.
Fair? What are you,
seven years old? Fair!
Tell you what.
You give us Lorelei Martins
we'll give you this guy.
That's fair.
No? Okay. Bye-bye.
Bastards.
Hey, no need to be so grumpy.
You got your wish.
You wanted them to vanish?
Vanished.
What is so funny?
They took our suspect.
- No, they took their suspect.
- Norris isn't our man?
Small hands, addicted to routine.
No way a man like that
strangles a woman on impulse.
- But the photos in his wallet
- Planted.
I took them
from Callie's apartment
for just such an occasion.
You know full well that is illegal
in 20 different ways.
- What about your promise to Bertram?
- I had my fingers crossed.
Didn't you wish for Mancini and Smith
to just disappear?
Well, voila, your wish
was granted, like magic.
Now we can focus
on catching the real killer
while the FBI's dealing
with Norris.
That is not the point.
"We're supposed to be rebuilding
our relationship with the FBI."
- Rebuilding trust.
- Trust is not an option.
Red John has a friend
inside the FBI.
If they get hold of Lorelei,
she will die or escape.
Oh, God, here we go.
How do you know that?
Red John told me.
Well, he was lying, of course,
to muddy the waters.
Why would he tell you
the truth?
Because he knows we'll assume
he's lying.
And he knows we'll begin to suspect
the truth anyway.
It's a double bluff
to conceal his friend.
Or he's lying
and he has no friend in the FBI.
Why are you so determined
to believe that?
Because I would like to feel
solid ground under my feet.
I would like to trust somebody
or something.
You know, you, with your wheels
within wheels...
you're driving me nuts.
- Hey, boss.
- Hey, Grace.
Where are we
with Karlsen and Lango?
Uh, looked into the phone records.
No calls in or out
for Lango that evening.
Callie Karlsen called
Nicola Karlsen at 7:15
18 minutes
before the 911 call.
Hey, boss. Where's the FBI?
They are pursuing other inquiries.
- Sweet!
- Listen to me.
The FBI is a fine organization
and they are our partners.
We need to work with them.
They deserve our respect and our trust.
- Am I clear?
- Yeah.
- Did you contact the sister?
- Yes.
She lives out in Boone.
She was out of contact
for two days at a swap meet in Tahoe.
Got home this morning.
- The local sheriff gave her the news.
- What's her story?
Oh, the Karlsen family used to own
half of Alameda county.
Lost it all in the crash of '06
parents died a year later...
highway collision.
Nicola is the older sister.
Single mom, two kids.
Jewelry designer is what
it says on her I.R.S. forms.
What about Lango?
Moved to town from L.A.
six months ago.
No rap sheet on him.
No relatives or friends nearby.
We went through his apartment.
Nothing.
Bare bones.
Mattress on the floor.
Running from something, maybe?
Keep digging on Lango.
It sounds promising.
Jane and I will go
talk to the sister.
You two go and canvass
the crime scene
like you should have instead
of fighting with the FBI!
- Yes, boss.
Hey, Yannick.
Agents.
- Thanks for your help.
- No problemo.
Just don't hit me, okay?
Funny.
Hey, no offense, but...
I never saw that before.
Law enforcement agents
fighting it out in the street?
You guys are hard-core, man!
Yes. Uh, so, anyway,
we started canvassing already.
Nothing useful so far.
- Let's check out the rest of...
- Yeah.
All right. Thank you very much
for your time. Appreciate it.
Saw a young fellow
over there...
same one they've been showing
on the TV...
got beat to death.
And you saw just one man?
- Rex Lango?
- Yes, sir.
Knocking on her door
about 6:30.
We were sitting out in the sun,
then we came inside.
Did you ever see him
around here before?
No, first time.
She didn't have visitors much.
And then later we heard
a scream from over that way
just a little short one,
like, uh, "Aah!"
- And you weren't concerned?
- Well, no.
At the time, I thought it was
you know, passion.
I said to Bucky, "Good for her".
"That Karlsen girl
got a boyfriend at last."
And what time was this?
I know what time it was
because we were checking
our lottery tickets on the TV.
It was 10 past 7:00.
Here's me thinking
her luck had changed
when really, she was dying.
Poor girl.
Hello. Nicola Larson?
Hi. Um, you must be the CBI.
We're very sorry
for your loss.
Uh, girls, could you maybe take
the boys to your place
watch some TV or something?
Sure. Come on, guys.
Let's go.
I was at a crafts fair
in the Sierras.
The hippie geniuses in charge
picked a place
with great vibes
and no cell phone reception.
So I didn't get this message.
"Nic!
Call me as soon as you can!"
I didn't get that call till last night
when I came home.
Then I called her,
and called...
and called, and then the sheriff
came by this morning.
Nicola, tell us about your sister.
To be honest, we haven't found
a motive yet.
Who would wanna hurt Callie?
I mean, she was a warm,
happy spirit.
Everybody loved her.
Did she have any failed relationships
in her past?
No.
What about feuds with neighbors
or financial disputes,
maybe somebody who felt burned
when your family's business
went under?
We paid off all the debts.
All of them.
That's why I'm here doing this...
And Callie was cleaning rooms
instead of going to college.
Wow, you make some
beautiful things here.
Thank you.
Do you know Rex Lango?
Is that the man
who died with her?
No, I've never heard
the name before.
Well, it seems that, uh...
Callie and Rex were about to drink
a very nice vintage champagne...
1975. About, uh, 500 bucks
a bottle, I'd guess.
At least.
That was the last
from my dad's cellar.
There's no way Callie'd take it
out of the fridge herself.
She'd been saving that bottle
for years
for a special occasion,
like a talisman.
She would've told you
if there was a relationship brewing
with her and Lango?
Yes. Absolutely.
We're very close.
Callie was not interested
in finding a man.
She wanted to go to college first
and get her career going.
And what kind of career
did she want?
She had all kinds of big hopes.
She was the optimist
of the two of us.
She always said our luck
was gonna turn somehow.
I always said...
"Don't hold your breath."
Oh, sorry.
Excuse me.
I have to take this.
- Hello?
- "There's good news, Jane."
The FBI folded on Lorelei Martins.
She's all yours.
Folded?
Well, that's not like them.
You want her or not?
Yes. I'm on my way.
Uh, we need to go soon.
That's all for now, Nicola.
But I want you to know
we're gonna do everything we can
to bring whoever did this to justice.
- Yes, we sure will.
- I don't really care who did this.
Justice for them
won't help Callie or me.
That was rude.
I'm sorry.
It's your job.
I'm sure you do it very well.
No apology needed.
You make a very valid point.
Can I ask you... how much is this
particular one?
- What are you thinking?
- She's ready to crack.
Nicola?
Lorelei.
I meant, what are you thinking
of the case we're working on now?
Well, that one's a puzzler, isn't it?
What the hell is the motive?
I don't think it was the sister.
I like her.
So did you buy that bracelet
for Lorelei?
No, just a whim.
I liked it.
When I talk to her,
I need to be alone.
You will be.
I mean, with nobody watching
or listening.
I need to be able
to tell her truthfully
that we are alone.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Just be careful.
Don't get pulled into her game.
- What game is that?
- I don't know. You tell me.
Well, I'm supposed to tell you
a game that you're thinking of?
Okay. Uh, you're thinking
of, uh, Twister?
Go ahead. Laugh.
But she's practically
the first person
since your wife that you've,
you know...
Ohh.
It wouldn't be surprising
if you had feelings for her.
She's a stepping stone
to Red John.
I knew that from the beginning.
I don't have any feelings for her.
Hello, Patrick.
Lorelei.
Is it just us, or are
your friends listening?
- "It's just us. We're alone."
- "Good."
"It's much nicer that way."
Sorry I didn't come
to visit you sooner.
I've been a little busy
with a case.
It's okay.
I've been enjoying
the peace and quiet.
Is there anything you need?
I'm fine.
Never mind about me.
How are you?
"Back to solving crimes, huh?"
Yeah.
Why do you bother?
You're trying to hold back
the tide with a broom.
What good are you doing?
I think...
you do it to be close
to Teresa Lisbon.
"I think you're a little bit
in love with her."
I-I do it to, uh...
pass the time.
What good are you doing?
Not much in here.
But I'll be out soon enough.
How and when is up
to Red John.
You think he'll get you outta this?
He'll kill you.
It's easier.
That's okay,
if that's what he wants.
You're that far under his control?
He'll kill you as well
if that's what he wants.
You just can't accept
the fact.
I can make you a better offer.
No killing.
I can get you outta here now...
today, if you want.
I can get you money,
a new identity
uh, set you up with a new life
far away from here.
- "You can do that?"
- "Yes, I can."
I can do anything you want
if you give me Red John.
I want...
your trust
and friendship.
- You have that.
- I don't believe you.
How can I make you believe?
Kiss me.
What does that prove?
First you say
you'll do anything I want
then you refuse
the first thing I ask for.
You're very complicated.
Let me get you outta here.
- I need time to think.
- Not for long.
I don't know how much longer
we're gonna get to keep you here.
We'll talk again this evening.
What are you? Huh?
Crazy?
- Excuse me?
- I told you to be careful.
I told you not to go over
the edge.
And I told you not to listen.
Don't be childish!
I am not your girlfriend.
I am an officer of the law.
How could I not listen?
You kissed her.
You offered to help her escape.
And I would ask her to marry me
if I thought she'd buy it.
- I was playing her.
- She's playing you.
We should've given her
to the feds.
Um, M.E. sent his report
on Callie and Rex.
Confirmed it's not possible
they killed each other.
And Callie had
a small white feather
lodged in the back
of her mouth.
- A feather, huh? Like from a pillow?
- Right.
Which suggests Callie
was strangled by hand
and suffocated with a pillow,
probably in that order.
Why two methods?
Two different people?
Or the killer wasn't
strong enough
- to complete the strangulation.
- Right.
- A woman?
- Women can strangle people.
Oh, believe me, I know I could.
Where's Cho and Rigsby?
I got a line on Rex Lango finally.
Changed his name.
Used to be Erzat Lonagul
out of Bakersfield.
Cho and Rigsby drove down there
to speak to his family.
Nobody could say his name,
so he changed it to Rex.
He was gonna be
a big businessman
and he thought
that sounded rich.
Rex Lango.
Was there any particular business
he was interested in?
You know, he was good
at computers.
But he didn't know yet exactly.
The Internet, robots
or whatever.
Any brushes with the law?
Shady friends?
No.
My cousin was a good man.
Ah!
He was a good man
and he's gone now, so be nice.
He was a bum!
He was not.
He nearly always had a job
and he was never
in trouble with the law.
Is that a bum?
He was never in trouble
because he was too sneaky!
The kid was stealing candy
and quarters
from before he could walk.
And then he would lie to your face
like a drug seller!
He was a dog
to the women always!
A bum!
Scheming, dishonest, greedy,
selfish womanizer.
Yeah, but not a criminal.
Just a creep.
He left Bakersfield two years ago
to avoid a paternity suit.
They had no idea he was in SAC.
Last they heard, he was in L.A.
Hmm. That's interesting.
So like I said,
it's a love triangle.
But we've got no jealous boyfriend
and I can't see Callie
dating a sleaze like him.
And she logged no calls
or texts to him, right?
Nope.
I'm waiting for her e-mail records.
I couldn't get them direct
from her P.C.
The hard drive is fried.
Oh. Well, that's why
he was there.
He was in tech support, right?
So he offers to fix her computer.
How could she refuse?
- And then what happened?
- I don't know.
I gotta run. Lorelei's on her way up
from holding.
Wait.
We still haven't resolved
our issue.
I don't think you should be
talking to Lorelei.
- You're too close.
- Well, I disagree.
I could put a stop to this right now.
- One word to Bertram about what you've...
- Please don't do that.
I know I can turn her.
I know I can.
And I promise you
I will be careful.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- Hey.
Stand down, man.
I'm taking charge of this prisoner.
I'm sorry.
What are you talking about?
This is a federal judge's warrant
transferring custody
- of Lorelei to the FBI.
- No, no, no. You can't do that.
- Back off.
- No, don't touch me.
- Hey, wait. Wha...?
- Let's go.
- I need you to step back, sir.
- Don't let them take me.
- Step back.
- Patrick!
- You can't just take her!
Back it up.
Patrick!
There isn't a choice.
We have to get her back.
Jane, the FBI outfoxed us.
Th-they only pretended
to give up Lorelei
while they were preparing
the warrant to take her.
We should've known they wouldn't fold.
Just deal with it.
I-I'd have to strong-arm a judge
and the FBI
into an arbitration hearing,
and even then...
Well, do it.
The FBI know
how to interrogate people.
They'll do a fine job.
They will either kill her,
or she'll escape.
And we will lose our best chance...
the best chance we have had
of getting to Red John.
Kill her? Uh, what... why?
The... the FBI?
D-don't be ridiculous.
Red John has a friend
high up in the FBI.
Oh, please.
Now how do you know that?
- He told me.
- Well, there you go.
If we don't get her, I will blow
this whole cover-up wide open.
The truth of Wainright's death,
all over the news.
If you do that,
this whole deal collapses
- and you go to jail.
- I don't care.
You call a hearing, or I will be
very glad to sing like a bird.
Well, I've studied all the documents
in this matter
and it is very clear to me
that all of you people
are lying through your teeth.
- Judge...
- No, I don't wanna know.
Whatever sordid errors
you're all conspiring
to cover up
I don't wanna know.
The sole purpose of this meeting
is to decide
who is best equipped to have custody
of Lorelei Martins.
I will decide in favor
of whichever side
irritates me the least.
I will tolerate no misbehavior
of any kind.
Proceed with care.
Your Honor, I would ask you
to simply to look at the record
of Patrick Jane.
Red John killed his family.
Lorelei Martins is a close confederate
of Red John.
How can this man possibly
treat her
with the clarity
and the objectivity required?
He's not a trained professional.
He's a vigilante.
And that alone
should disqualify the CBI
from custody in this matter.
For many years,
I have been pursuing Red John.
I know this case better
than anybody else.
These people, they don't know
how to make Lorelei Martins talk.
- I do.
- If I may interject
Miss Martins tells us
that she has had sexual
relations with Mr. Jane.
That may be the source
of his confidence.
Is that so?
Yes, it is.
We have a relationship.
Uh, that's a good thing.
That's how you turn people.
I'd expected a denial,
to be honest.
Do we need to continue?
Um, that does tend
to disqualify you, Mr. Jane.
So, um, if you have
nothing further...
She's already given me
valuable information.
- Let's not stop me now.
- Valuable information like what?
With all due respect,
this is not the time
or the place to share the details.
If you wanna see
Lorelei Martins again
this is both the time
and the place.
She told me that
all Red John's friends...
have a secret sign they use
to identify each other.
And what is it?
Go on.
They carry a glass bead
in their pocket...
blood red,
the size of a pea.
- Lorelei showed me hers.
- That's it? Un-provable trivia?
- It proves she trusts me.
- It proves nothing.
Can we stop this farce now?
It is a bit thin, Mr. Jane.
Is that all you have?
No.
- Not at all.
- Well?
Red John has an accomplice...
- inside the FBI.
- Come on.
Judge, this man is just spinning
fantasies now.
Yes. Yes, you would say that.
I saw you.
What do you mean by that?
When I mentioned the glass bead
you suddenly looked very guilty
and you glanced
at your right-hand jacket pocket.
What's in there, Mancini?
This... this is the same thing
that you did to Norris.
- What? Who?
- Son of a bitch...
- Agent.
- What's in your pocket, Mancini?
There's nothing... this is
a childish trick, Your Honor.
Th-this man has just planted
a bead on me.
Uh, let's be clear.
I have not touched you.
Everybody in this room
has seen that.
But you're saying
that there is in fact
a red glass bead
in your pocket.
- Is that what you're saying?
- No!
You're putting words in my mouth.
Show us what's in your pockets, agent.
- You don't understand...
- Show us!
He planted it.
He planted it!
But he didn't touch you, did he?
You son of a bitch!
- Mancini!
- Come here!
- Order! Order!
- Get over here!
Agent Shultz! This is a disgrace.
- Ah, well done.
- Good job. When do we get her back?
Uh, judge says we can pick her up
at county jail tomorrow.
Did, uh, Mancini really throw
a bottle at you?
Yes, he did, and then he proceeded
to chase me
through the state house,
but failed to catch me.
Congratulations.
Another mortal enemy made.
You should be very proud.
Uh, meanwhile,
we've got a case to solve.
Well, let's get busy then, boss.
So let's just assume that Rex
was at Callie's apartment
to fix her computer.
What happened next?
How does that escalate
to a double murder?
Well, maybe the computer
is key.
Maybe there was something important
on the hard drive.
She cleans hotel rooms.
What could be important?
How does that connect
her lipstick on his cheek?
He couldn't fix her computer
so they made out instead?
Well, there are other reasons
for kissing someone.
Celebration, for instance,
hence the champagne.
What would they be celebrating?
Well, maybe the kiss was
"Thanks for trying to fix my computer."
So who's the third person here?
What are we missing?
Sorry I'm late.
They're setting up a stage
for the state lottery prize
presentation at the capital.
- Traffic on L Street was crazy.
- Oh, the lottery.
They should do that
at Raley Field
or someplace
where they have parking.
Uh, when did computer forensics
say they'd be done
with Callie's hard drive?
End of the week, but...
- What?
- Callie's sister... Nicola.
You have her phone number?
Ladies and gentlemen, friends
it is my very great pleasure
to introduce to you at this time
the lucky winner of this year's
biggest lottery jackpot.
Please welcome to the stage
a young woman
who is now worth $56 million...
Valerie Whittaker.
Come on out here, Valerie.
- There you go, Valerie.
- Wow!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you!
Thank you so, so, so much.
I'm so blessed. Thank you.
Valerie, how you feeling?
Oh... I'm just in shock.
It's like a movie.
- Any plans for the money?
- Not yet.
I'm gonna take a flier.
Do you happen to know a Tom Yannick
of the Sacramento Police?
- No.
- Are you sure?
'Cause I'm pretty sure.
Who else would've had the opportunity?
A random intruder? Unlikely.
Tom Yannick.
He's not your boyfriend then?
Okay. Just a moment.
Valerie, this is Nicola Karlsen.
She's Callie Karlsen's sister
the woman that was brutally murdered
for the lottery ticket
that won that check
you're holding there.
Would you tell her
you don't know Tom Yannick?
- I...
- Aha!
- You told me nothing would go wrong!
- No! Stop, stop!
Thomas Yannick...
you're under arrest for murder.
Yes.
This doesn't belong to you.
We're gonna have to get
the name changed.
Do you have a... marker, pen?
Callie was checking
the lottery numbers
while Rex tried to fix
her computer.
She won $56 million.
"She kissed Rex"
"got the champagne
out of the fridge"
"then she called her sister."
Then greed got
the better of Rex
and he tried to strangle Callie
so he could steal the ticket.
"But she killed him instead
with a champagne bottle"
and called 911.
Then half-strangled
and in shock, she fainted.
And that's where you come in.
"You found the two of them, you saw the
lottery ticket and the champagne bottle."
"You put 2 and 2 together...
quite the detective."
"So you killed Callie."
You think about it for a while,
or you just go for it?
I-I thought about it
for a while.
I felt bad for her.
- But $56 million, man.
- Yeah.
Well, you should've thought
about it a while longer.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
You are such a good man.
Thank you.
Sorry to interrupt, Nicola
but Jane and I have
to pick up a prisoner.
Thank you.
Pleasure.
Come on!
What is taking so long?
Relax. She'll be here.
Look, I-I'm sorry, by the way.
For what? There's a long list
of possibilities.
Yeah, well, this is more of a...
general purpose apology.
Use it for your top issue.
Thanks.
- Here you go.
- Who's this?
5467B.
That's not her.
There's been a mistake.
No mistake.
Her paperwork's all in order.
It's the only
Lorelei Martins we got.
"Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode."